<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="danksagungen" xml:lang="de"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title xml:base="" xml:id="danksagungen.title">Acknowledgements</title>

  <section xml:id="boris_karnikowski">
    <title xml:id="boris_karnikowski.title">Boris Karnikowski</title>

    <para>In particular, I would like to thank Boris Karnikowski of Pearson
    Education Germany (Adison-Wesley) in Munich (<uri
    xlink:href="http://www.pearson.de/">http://www.pearson.de/</uri>). Boris
    has pushed the German version of this book through at the publishers and
    for this I am very grateful. I also want to thank him for his patience.
    The original German version of the project was delayed by more than a
    year.</para>

    <para>Boris Karnikowski has the technical talent of spotting new IT topics
    in their whole significance. But most remarkable in my eyes is his ability
    to give both positive and negative, honest feedback to an author about a
    text or an idea.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="lektorat">
    <title xml:id="lektorat.title">Editorial Office</title>

    <para>Writing a book on a particular topic is one thing, but turning it
    into a book that actually reads well over several hundred pages is an
    entirely different story. This is only possible if you have a good
    editorial team, because often the book's author can no longer see the wood
    for the trees.</para>

    <section xml:id="dominik_bamberger">
      <title xml:id="dominik_bamberger.title">Dominik Bamberger</title>

      <para>Dominik Bamberger is working as Ruby on Rails programmer for the
      company SUSE LINUX Products GmbH in Nuremberg, Germany. As Rails expert
      he has spotted some mistakes as technical editor of the book and often
      provided helpful ideas for how to structure the content.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="brigitte_hamerski">
      <title xml:id="brigitte_hamerski.title">Brigitte Hamerski</title>

      <para>Brigitte Hamerski (<uri
      xlink:href="http://www.lektorat-hamerski.de">http://www.lektorat-hamerski.de</uri>)
      once again did excellent work in copy editing this book. Without her
      work, the text would be riddled with typos, wrong punctuation and
      grammatical errors. Above all, it would be full of repetitive sentences
      and sometimes overly long and complicated descriptions of things that
      are really quite simple.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="danksagungen_rockstars">
    <title xml:id="danksagungen_rockstars.title">Ruby and Rails
    Rockstars</title>

    <para>There are also quite a few Ruby and Rails developers to whom I owe
    thanks. Funnily enough, many of them are also competitors, because they
    also offer books, videos or training on Rails or Ruby. The Rails community
    contains many colorful and sometimes rather egocentrical characters. I now
    believe that this is even necessary for their success. I am listing people
    that have been important in one way or another for the creation of this
    book, and without whom this book would probably not have been written in
    the way it was. This does however not mean that I always agree with these
    people. ;-)<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Yukihiro Matsumoto (a.k.a. Matz)</para>

          <para>As inventor of Ruby, I surely owe him the greatest thanks. His
          book "The Ruby Programming Language" (O'Reilly Media) is one of the
          best books on programming languages that I have ever read. I also
          want to thank the main author David Flanagan.</para>

          <para>Information on Matz can be found at <uri
          xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yukihiro_Matsumoto">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yukihiro_Matsumoto</uri></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>David Heinemeier Hansson</para>

          <para>As inventor of Rails, I also logically owe him great
          thanks.</para>

          <para>David's homepage can be found at <uri
          xlink:href="http://www.loudthinking.com/">http://www.loudthinking.com/</uri></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Dave Thomas</para>

          <para>Dave has done so much for the Ruby and Rails community with
          his numerous books and his publishing house The Pragmatic
          Programmers, LLC. (see also <uri
          xlink:href="http://www.pragprog.com/">http://www.pragprog.com/</uri>).
          Together with Chad Fowler, he showed me a great deal in two Rails
          seminars in the USA. He has been a leading Rails programmer right
          from the start and is right up there at the top with his impressive
          knowledge.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Chad Fowler</para>

          <para>I approached Rails in several stages and once more with each
          new version. But it took years until it finally clicked in my head.
          A Rails training course held by Dave Thomas and Chad Fowler in
          Denver Colorado was an important step for me in this process. Like
          Dave, Chad has incredible knowhow of Ruby and Rails.</para>

          <para>Chad's homepage can be found at <uri
          xlink:href="http://chadfowler.com/">http://chadfowler.com/</uri></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Ryan Bates</para>

          <para>With his <uri
          xlink:href="http://railscasts.com/">http://railscasts.com/</uri>
          program, Ryan is a veritable institution in the Rails community.
          Each week there is at least one new screencast on a particular topic
          to do with Rails. Definitely highly recommended!</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="danksagungen_helfer">
    <title xml:id="danksagungen_helfer.title">Helpers</title>

    <para>The following people have contributed to this book in one form or
    another already in its very early stages and I am very grateful to
    them:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Philipp Kempgen</para>

          <para>Philipp has read large parts of the book, corrected the
          content and often provided positive influences by asking critical
          questions on individual aspects.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Pratik Sinha</para>

          <para>Has helped with DocBook problems. He created the XSLT for
          exporting to PDF and HTML.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Pratik Naik</para>

          <para>Pratik has helped with questions and problems regarding
          ActiveRecord.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="danksagungen_twitter">
    <title xml:id="danksagungen_twitter.title">Twitter</title>

    <para>Twitter has repeatedly proved to be an interesting source of
    information and feedback while I was writing this book. In particular, I
    would like to thank the following Twitter accounts:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>@priceted</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>@swrobel</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>@Bumi</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>@Sutto</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="danksagungen_leser">
    <title xml:id="danksagungen_leser.title">Readers</title>

    <para>Just as I did with my book on Asterisk (see <uri
    xlink:href="http://www.das-asterisk-buch.de">http://www.das-asterisk-buch.de</uri>),
    I have made this book available on the Internet before it was published in
    book form in its German version. For my publishers, this is always a tough
    situation, but for me as author it's a great source of feedback. Here I am
    going to list the Beta readers who have sent me feedback that helped
    improve the text, or pointed out logic errors.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>anonymous</para>

        <para>Often I get tips or feedback from people who deal with entirely
        different programming languages in their work (mostly Java) and who
        prefer to remain anonymous. Thank you very much for your help!</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Ingo Plate</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Jörg Bellmann</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Patric Hansen</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
